Benjamin Paulsen

Developer & Designer

Website Game Portfolio Email Phone bjpaulsen.github.io gamesbyboon.itch.io bjpaulse@ucsc.edu (831) 428-3680

SKILLS

Open. Respectful of different ways of thinking, open to feedback, and communicative.

Skilled. Developed in C#, C++, C, Java, Javascript, Python, HTML/CSS, and MIPS Assembly.

Versatile. Experienced with Unity, Godot, Angular, Aseprite, PureData, UNIX, Git.

EXPERIENCE

Tech4Good Lab - Undergraduate Research Fellow, Frontend Developer

JANUARY 2020 - PRESENT

- Conducted a user research study as the lead developer for an online learning platform.
- Co-led a team of developers to create a team-building platform using Angular.

UC Santa Cruz, Learning Support Services - Computer Science Tutor

SEPTEMBER 2019 - MARCH 2019

- Taught groups of university students how to program, debug, and problem-solve.
- Learned how to better accommodate students with diverse needs and learning differences.

Game Development Projects - Designer, Programmer, Artist

DECEMBER 2017 - PRESENT

- Created multiple original video games from scratch, published at <u>gamesbyboon.itch.io</u>.
- Developed practical experience with game engines, algorithmic music, art, and promotion.

Santa Cruz Parks And Recreation, Scotts Valley Library - MAKE Lab Intern

JUNE 2018 - AUGUST 2018

- Ran popular technology showcase events at the Scotts Valley Library.
- Taught children, teens, adults, and seniors about using computers, tools and tech.

Winner at HackACM 2019 - Hackathon Beginner Category

APRIL 2019

• Built a loop pedal musical performance tool in Java with a small team in under 12 hours.

EDUCATION

University of California, Santa Cruz - Undergraduate in Computer Science: Game Design FALL 2018 - PRESENT

Benjamin Paulsen

Developer & Designer

Website bjpaulsen.github.io Email bjpaulse@ucsc.edu Phone (831) 428-3680

REFERENCES

David Lee - Faculty Advisor, Tech4Good Lab

Professor of Computational Media at the University of California, Santa Cruz dlee105@ucsc.edu

Mason Pierce - Lead Developer, Tech4Good Lab

Tech4Good Fellow mason.pierce@ucsc.edu

Jaqueline Morales - Supervisor, UCSC Learning Support Services

Assistant Director of Tutoring jmoral11@ucsc.edu (831)-459-3462